# SEAN FARIA

Phone: (305) 301-7140 | Email: sfari004@gmail.com

Website: http://www.seanfaria.com

Address: 22429 SW 88<sup>th</sup> path, Cutler Bay, Florida 33190

# **Objective**

I am currently working as a Cloud Engineer with over 3 years of hands-on experience in Development, Architecture, and Production Environments. Seeking a position where my technical background and continuedgrowth and interests are supported for our bilateral success. I am looking forward to new challenges.

## Skills and Certifications

#### **Skills**

AWS, Azure, GCP, SQL Server, MYSQL, Windows, PowerShell, JavaScript, Linux, Apache, Tomcat, Git, Python, Jenkins, New Relic, Terraform.

#### Certification

AWS Cloud Practitioner – March 2018 AWS Solutions Architect – August 2018

### Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE-INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - Barry University - Miami Shores -2014-2016

# Work Experience

### CLOUD ENGINEER - PARK STREET IMPORTS, LLC- Miami, Florida - June 2019 - Present

- Automate patches, software upgrades, and backups using AWS service (AWS Backup, AWS SSM)
- Collaborating with development teams to evaluate and identify optimal cloud solutions.
- Orchestrating and automating cloud-based platforms throughout the company.
- Educating teams on the implementation of new cloud technologies and initiatives.
- Designing, developing and deploying on cloud-based systems.
- Modify and enhance current CI/CD pipeline to support the different deployment flavors Ensuring efficient functioning of data storage and processing functions in accordance with cloud security best practices.
- Identifying, analyzing, and resolving infrastructure vulnerabilities and application deployment issues.
- Regularly reviewing existing systems and making recommendations for improvements.
- Interacting with clients, providing cloud support, and making recommendations based on client needs.

### SOFTWARE CONSULTANT - IB USA INC. - Sunrise, Florida - July 2016 - May 2019

- Automate patches, software upgrades, and backups using PowerShell and group policy.
- Provide level I/II and III support for ship to shore communication servers and software.
- Build, administer and maintain environments in AWS (Amazon Web Services) and Microsoft Azure.
- Perform QA testing on application to ensure that key features function in web environment.
- Develop and integrate solutions in PowerShell Scripting to maximize efficiency in transport using FTP/SFTP.
- Integrate highly available/fault tolerant cloud environments for customers using AWS/Azure best practices.
- SQL Server and Windows Server 2008/2012/2016 administrator
- Infrastructure analysis to diagnose connection issues between database servers and application servers using various security tools and networking techniques.
- Managed billing resources to maintain budget constrictions and become more efficient.
- Develop, deployment and migration of onsite services to the Cloud.
- Create VPN access for offsite personnel using AWS best practices.

#### INTERN - BARRY UNIVERSITY - Miami Shores, Florida - Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

- Installed and configured computer hardware operating systems and applications.
- Identified, diagnosed and solved system hardware or software faults.
- Responsible for ensuring data sanitization on computer before repurposing, using dban.
- Prioritized and managed open tickets.
- Administered user account changes within active directory focusing on access controls.